# Rimi Al Farwan-Gokool

# Full Stack Developer

Address C01, Rubis

Pointe aux Sables

Phone +230 57052854

E-mail rimi.alfarwan@gmail.com

**Date of birth** 1988-06-25

**Facebook** 

https://www.facebook.com/rimi.alfarwan

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rimi-al-farwan-gokool-88970999/

Rimi is a results-oriented full stack web developer with 5+ years experience developing, testing, and maintaining enterprise software applications. I design and develop advanced applications from use cases and functional requirements within an agile team. I always expose myself to new technologies to make sure that the company I work for remains the leader in setting industry standards throughout the years. What makes me impressive is that I believe in myself. I believe that doing things is the best strategy to establish and sustain the links between learning and knowledge.

# **Experience**

2017-02 - present

#### **Full Stack Team Leader**

Linkopia Mauritius Ltd

#### Responsibilities:

- Products designing and prototyping which meet clients' requirements.
- Develop logic for apps.
- Build Restful API solutions as a third party service.
- Develop BI systems using complex relational databases for creating enterprises' KPIs.
- Supervise a small team of developers.

2014-02 - 2017-02

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Linkopia Mauritius Ltd

#### Responsibilities:

- build web applications on a LAMP stack environment.
- Create responsive front-end web pages using HTML5/CSS3/Jquery/Bootstrap.
- Integrate responsive emails and newsletters with the standard markups, fully supported by all email clients.

2013-08 - 2014-02

#### IT support officer

Infoclub Ltd

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Teaching City and Guilds programs.
- · Network installation.
- Maintaining PCs and peripherals.

## **Education**

2015-08 - present University of Technology, Mauriitus

**BSC Software Engineering** 

2009-08 - 2012-12 **Damascus University** 

**BEng Information Technology** 

### **Certificates**

2018-06

Mobile Application Developer - Mastery Award for Students 2016

#### **Interests**

Football

Computer science and technology

Entrepreneur

Swimming

eSports

# **Skills**

Front end Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Jquery framework.

LAMP stack development including PHP MVC Frameworks (Codeigniter) and CMS (Wordpress).

Maintaining and developing solutions using advanced databases: My-SQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle.

Web Services: SOAP based and Restful APIs.

Developing cloud platforms with Amazon web services, including services like EC2, VPC, S3, RDS, SES and Cloudfront.

Online firewalls like Cloudflare and Incapsula.

Hybrid and native mobile development, including Android Studio and IBM Mobile First framework.

Business Intelligence applications and analytics tools: Sisense and Tableu.

Al and Machine learning using Keras and tensorflow.

Game development using construct 2 and unreal engine.

ASP.net with C# and VB

**JAVA Programming** 

Exposure to the MEAN stack: Mongo db, Express.js, Angular.js and node.js.

Search Engine Optimization, familiar with Google Tag Manager and Analytics.

Adobe suit: Photoshop, Illustrator.

#### Languages

English - Professional working proficiency

Arabic - Native

French - Limited working proficiency